Milislav Demerec Papers 1919-1966 Mss.B.D394
American Philosophical Society
- Series IV. Photographs, ca.1922-1960; 0.75 linear feet
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec at desk, Woods Hole. Profile view, full image, more of room visible in background, 1928; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec, air raid warden identification card, Oyster Bay, New York, 1942; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec at desk, Woods Hole, Image: 3.5 x 5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec and unidentified woman outside unidentified building, ca. 1965; Image: 3.25 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec on beach, in shorts and shirt, checking watch or other small object, ca. 1965; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec on a beach, Image: 3.25 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - Sir Ronald Aylmer Fisher, 1890-1962, Image: 3.25 x 5, 1 photoprint
  - Sir Ronald Aylmer Fisher, holding coat, standing near fence with field in background, ca. 1920; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec in Japan, 1956; Image: 3.25 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with Japanese Geneticists at International Genetics Symposia (Tokyo and Kyoto, Japan) September 6-12, 1956, Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with Mrs. Demerec arriving at Japan, September 3, 1956, walking up airport stairs, Image: 4 x 5; Moriwaka, Dr
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec's arrival in Japan, 1956 September 3; Image: 3 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec's arrival in Japan, Image: 3.25 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec talking with Japanese panelist, probably at conference, with genetics charts on blackboard in background, 1956; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with H. Kikkawa, 1956; Image: 4 x 5
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec in Japan, Image: 3 x 4, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with unidentified woman, Image: 3.25 x 4.25, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec conferring with unidentified woman at Carnegie Institution of Washington (Cold Spring Harbor, Long Island, New York)
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with unidentified man on beach, Woods Hole, Image: 2.5 x 4.5, 1 photoprint
  - M. (Milislav) Demerec with unidentified man on beach at Marine Biological Laboratory (Woods Hole, Massachusetts), ca. 1920; Image: 4 x 5
  - Demerec, half length formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Half length, 3/4 view of Demerec.
  - Demerec, half length profile, sitting in laboratory, wearing sweater, 1928; 1.0 Photograph(s); Demerec sitting in laboratory with microscope and beakers on table.
  - Demerec, half length portrait, seated with bow tie, 1928, July; 1.0 Photograph(s); Demerec, seated at table in Woods Hole laboratory with microscope.
  - Blakeslee seated at desk writing with pen, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Autographed half length portrait of Blakeslee seated at desk pen in hand.
  - Bonnevie (?), formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Formal 3/4 view portrait of woman.
    General note
    Hand written note on back of photograph: "Ch. Bonnevie, 1872 - "
  - Calvin Bridges, formal portrait, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Autographed bust length portrait of Calvin Blackman Bridges.
  - Shull, formal profile, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Autographed formal profil of George Harrison Shull.
  - Haldane, Farlington (?), Demerec, and Stadler standing outside, trees in background, 1938; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length group portrait of men standing outside, drinking from steins.
  - Demerec and Sir Charles Harington in conversation, 1957; 1.0 Photograph(s); Candid 3/4 length photograph of Demerec and Harington.
  - Two women working in laboratory, seated, n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two women, one looking into microscope, the other working with a beaker, sitting at a table in a laboratory.
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington road sign, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Sign for the "Carnegie Institution of Washington Department of Genetics, Station for Experimental Evolution"
  - Dr. Blakeslee's Sun Hat Means Summer Has Come, with Jimmy Potter, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Blakeslee and Potter standing outside, building in background.
    Title taken from handwritten note on album page beneath photograph.
  - Bob Stewart and Maydelle Bishop Finally Got Engaged, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of man and woman standing in green house.
  - Arn Sparrow, Phil Bridges, Taylor Hinton standing outside, plants in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of three men standing in front of plants.
    Hand written not on album page under photograph: "The Dog-House Boys -- Arn Sparrow, Phil Bridges, Taylor Hinton."
  - Twin Dresses on Eileen Sutton and Kitty Brehme Warren, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait of two women in identicial attire.
  - A Carnegie Quartet -- Barbara Korsch, Taylor Hinton, Eileen Sutton, Arn Sparrow, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length group protrait, outside near plants.
  - Lunch on the Lawn -- Lou Stillwell, Jimmy Potter, Janis Baker, Ber Kaufmann, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Four people sitting on grass, tress in background.
  - Dr. Demerec spoke with the aid of the big salivary map, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Demerec standing outside holding a larg folded map.
    Hand written text on album page below photograph: "The daily Drosophila Seminars were among the nicest things that happened all summer. Dr. Demerec spoke with the aid of the big salivary map."
  - Ugo Fano Leaving a Drosophila Seminar, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Fano passing through a door.
  - Ber Kaufmann and Al Miller, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full lenght portrait, outside.
  - Vernon Bryson, standing outside of building, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait, outside, against a building.
  - Jim Neel and Al Miller standing outdoors with car in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length group portrait, outside.
    Hand written not on album page under photograph: "Carnegie guests included Jim Neel and Al Miller."
  - Dr. J. W. Gowen and Alvin Nason standing outside near plants, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait, outside with tress in backgrond.
  - The Carnegie Biol. Lab Tennis Tournament -- Dr. J. G. Carlson on the Court, Betty Fairbanks and Jim Neel on the Sidelines, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of volley ball game, three spectators sitting in grass.
  - The Carlsons and Patsey Taylor, sitting outdoors on grass, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three people sitting on grass.
    Hand written note on album page under photograph, in reference to APSimg7225: "Watching another match -- the Carlsons and Patsey Taylor."
  - Dr. Tallman and Barabara Burks sitting on beach with water and sky in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Man and woman sitting on beach.
    Hand written note on album page under photograph: "Swimming off the sandspit -- Dr. Tallman and Barbara Burks."
  - Carlson, Warmke and Dunham outdoors in bathing suits, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three men, one sitting, outside in bathing suits.
  - Kottie Klem and Bill Kempner on beach, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Man and woman on beach, water and trees in background.
  - Swimming off the dock, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Swimmers sitting and standing on dock, surrounded by water.
  - Harold Abramsom completely surrounded by water, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Man swimming, two people on dock.
  - House with trees, plants, and driveway, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); View of house behind trees.
    Hand written note on album page below photograph: "Nichols."
  - T. L. Smith, standing outside in front of plants, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length portrait, standing in front of plants.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "A biol. lab personality -- T. L. Smith."
  - Blackford -- Eric and Ruth Ponder with Barbara Abramson and Molly Davson, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three women and one man sitting outside.
  - Dorothy Wrinch standing near low fence, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); full length portrait, outside near rocking chair with tree in background.
  - Mrs. Sansome, Eileen, Dr. Huskins during the Genetics Society Meetings at Woods Hole, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of one man and two women standing on steps outside of a building.
    Title taken from handwritten note on album page.
  - Mrs. Sansome, Eillen Sutton, Barbara Korsch sitting on steps outside of building, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three women sitting outside on steps, child standing in open door in background.
    Photograph taken during Genetics Society Meeting at Woods Hole, Summer 1940.
  - Group of men and women standing outside with trees and car in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); 1/2 length view of three men in foreground, with other people and car in background.
  - Embarking for the Genetics Society Picnic -- Whiting and Weiss, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Title taken from handwritten note on album page beneath photograph. Photograph taken during Genetics Society Meeting at Woods Hole, Summer 1940.
  - Four people standing on small island surrounded by water, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Far view of small island with lighthouse and four people, surrounded by wather.
  - The Glasses and Dr. Whiting, on boat with water in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); 1/2 lenght view of three people on boat, water in background.
  - Demerec, Hollaender, Sax Nebel and Fano in conversation aboard a boat, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Five men gathed together in coversation.
    Handwritten note on album page: "Great thoughts on board the Winifred -- Demerec, Hollaender, Sax, Nebel, with Fano Hovering Overhead."
  - Demerec and Whiting outside on porch, laughing, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Demerec leaning on handrail and Whiting standing on porch.
    Photograph taken during 3rd Gene Coference, 1940
  - Ugo and Lilla Fano, Mrs. Sax, Mrs. Carlson, Carlson, and Sax standing outside on sidewalk with buildings in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of group standing outside.
    Photograph taken during 3rd Gene Coference, 1940.
  - The Stadlers walking across a street, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of man and woman walking across a street. Buildings and car in background.
  - Uber, Wrinch, and Mazia standing near a low fence with house in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men and one woman standing outside.
  - Demerec and Dunn standing outside with tree in background, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - Kaufmann, Demerec, Dobzhansky, and Fano posing around Dobzhansky's new car, 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Four men posing around automobile.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "The Dobzansky's beautiful new car, completely surrounded by big shots -- Kaufmann, Demerec, Dobzhansky, Fano."
  - Dr. Andre Dreyfuss, standing outside in snow, full length portrait, 1944, February 11; 1.0 Photograph(s); Man in coat and hat standing outside in snow.
  - Dr. Andre Dreyfuss, standing outside in snow, 3/4 length portrait, 1944, February 11; 1.0 Photograph(s); Man in coat and hat standing outside in snow, building in background.
  - Two men standing on beach, one in swimming suit, one wearing a tie, ca. 1940; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men on beach, seated woman in background.
  - Demerec walking down a street, with house and lake in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Demerec walking.
    Handwritten note on album page beneath photograph: "Long Island Biological Laboratory, Summer 1941. The Director."
  - L. C. Dunn, B. Ephrussi, C. Stern sitting outside, building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men sitting, one leaning against a low wall, building in background.
    Hand written note on album page above photograph: "The Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Genes and Chromosome Structure, June 18 - July 2."
  - D. F. Jones, M. M. Rhoades, W. R. Singleton standing outside, building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); 1/2 length view of three men outside building.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "Some corn men, including two editors of 'Genetics' -- D. F. Jones, M. M. Rhoades, W. R. Singleton." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - L. J. Stadler and S. Luria standing outside laughing, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); 3/4 length view of two men standing outside building.
    Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - C. L. Huskins standing outside near low wall, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Huskins with hills and trees in background.
  - C. L. Huskins and F. Schrader standing outside in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); 1/2 length view of two men, trees in background.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "Something being said about the spidle by C. L. Huskins and F. Schrader." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - R. R. Gates and T. S. Painter sitting outside, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men seated in wooden chairs, people and building in background.
  - M. Delbruck and W. M. Stanley, sitting outside in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men sitting outside.
  - L. J. Stadler and C. Stern, sitting outside in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men sitting on wodden chairs.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "Plans being laid by L. J. Stadler and C. Stern." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - Jack Schultz and Curt Stern standing outside, ivy covered building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men standing outside.
  - P. A. Cole and Albert Claude, standing outside in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s)
  - Some physicists -- M. Delbruck, S. Luria, F. Exner, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men sitting, one standing, outside in convesation.
    Title taken from handwritten note on album page beneath photograph. Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - I. Fanduhen, R. D. Boche, F. M. Uber, sitting outside, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of three men sitting outside in wooden chairs.
  - D. Riddle standing outside, holding cigarette, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of D. Riddle standing outside, women in background.
  - Symposium Intermission, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group of people standing outside during symposium intermission.
  - Conference on the sand -- W. M. Stanley, J. W. Gowen, A. E. Mirsky, and M. Delbruck, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three men sitting on beach, one man leaning over in coversation, children and water in background.
  - Demerec on the beach in bathing suit with man and woman, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Demerec sitting on beach in bathing suit, next to a man and woman.
    Handwritten note on album page beneath photograph: "The director admits he has gained weight." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - A. E. Mirsky, J. Schultz and M. Perrod, standing on beach, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Three men standing on beach, one wearing a bathing suit.
  - Demerec walking on beach in bathing suit, talking to unidentified man, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Demerec on beach.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "The director organizing somebody." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - P. T. Ives sitting on beach, people and cars in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of man sitting on beach, line of cars in background.
  - C. B. Davenport walking on beach, water in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of Davenport walking on beach.
  - Dorathy Klem, standing outside in coat, trees in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of woman standing outside.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "Two people who kept the wheels of the institution turning -- Dororthy Klem and Jimmy de Tomasi" (second name referes to APSimg7274). Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - Jimmy de Tomasi standing outside, house in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of man standing in street, house in background.
    Hand written note on previous album page: "Two people who kept the whells of the institution turning -- Dorothy Klem and Jimmy de Tomasi" (the former name referes to APSimg7274). Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - Barbara McClintock standing outside, building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full lenght view of McCintock standing outside.
  - Symposium recorder with Carton and Berwind, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Woman sitting on grass with two kittens, car in background.
  - Sewall Wright standing outside, plants and building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of man standing in front of plants.
  - Arn Sparrow, Dick Ayr, Dr. A. M. Banta, Taylor Hinton and Kim Atwood posing outside, trees and building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Five men posing in seated positions.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "The sheep shed crew -- Arn Sparrow, Dick Ayr, Dr. A. M. Banta, Taylor Hinton." Photograph taken during Ninth Symposium on Quantitative Biology -- Genes and Chromosome Structure, 1941.
  - Group of men standing outside of building during the Genetics Society Meeting, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s)
    Accruals note
    Full length view of group of men standing outside.
    Photograph taken during the Genetics Society of America Meeting, August 27-29, 1941.
  - The H. J. Mullers, A. Weinstein, The C. Lindegens, standing outside, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of group of people standing outside, building in background.
  - F. M. Hott and P. B. Sawin standing outside, in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men, building in background.
  - L. C. Dunn and E. Caspari standing outside, in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men standing outside, building in background.
  - M. Demerec, W. P. Spencer, B. P. Sonnenblick standing outside, in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full view of three men standing outside talking, with plants and building in background.
  - A. Hollaender and N. H. Giles standing outside in conversation, plants in foreground, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); 1/2 length view of two men standing outside, plants in foreground.
  - B. Ephrussi and L. C. Dunn sitting outside, in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men sitting along wall, outside.
  - At the Society picnic -- Kimballs and Carlsons, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Two men and two women sitting on the grass, one man smoking a pipe.
    Title taken from handwritten note on album page beneath photograph. Photograph taken during the Genetics Society of America Meeting, August 27-29, 1941.
  - Demerec and the Secretary-Treasurer of the Cold Springs Harbor Laboratory standing outside, in conversation, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full length view of two men standing outside, plants in background.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "The secretary-treasurer and the commissar." Photograph taken during the Genetics Society of America Meeting, August 27-29, 1941.
  - E. E. Jones and C. J. Lynch, standing outside with mouse trap, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full view of two women, one wearing a hat, both with one foot on a wire cage.
  - M. Whittinghill, standing outside with trees, flowers and building in background, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full lenth view of man dressed in white, standing outside.
  - M. Gordon standing outside, near open window of building, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full view of man standing outside along wall of building.
  - Edgar Anderson and B. P. Kaufmann standing outside, 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Full view of two men dressed in white standing outside.
    Hand written note on album page beneath photograph: "Two big shots -- Edgar Anderson and B. P. Kaufmann."
  - Unidentified men around a table, foreground figure blurry, ca. 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group of men around a table, examining corn.
    Appears to be the same scene depicted in APSimg7293 and maybe APSimg4380.
  - Unidentified men sitting around table, figure in background blurry, ca. 1941; 1.0 Photograph(s); Group of men in room.
    Appears to be the same scene depicted in APSimg7292 and maybe APSimg4380.
  - William Bateson's visit to Cornell University, 1922; Image: 20 x 26 cm., mount 31 x 36 cm., 2 photoprints
  - Vannevar Bush, n.d.; Image: 35 x 29 cm., 1 print lithograph; Montgomery, Eugene A
  - Cornell University, Department of Plant Breeding, n.d.; Image: 26 x 33 cm., mount 31 x 39 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Genetics Society of America, Chelsey Hotel, Atlantic City, New Jersey, December 28, 1932, Image: 31 x 52 cm., 1 photoprint
  - Bacteriophagi-resistant mutants in Escherichia coli, 1945; Image: 36 x 31 cm., 1 photoprint
  - International Botanical Congress, 4th, Ithaca, New York, 1926. Agronomy and Genetics, Image: 20 x 57 cm., 1 photoprint
- Series V. Reprints, 1921-1968; 6.0 vol. (Volume 1-6)
  Numerous reprints of Demerec's works bound in six notebooks.
  Bacterial genetics; Bibliographical matters; Cancer, chemotherapy; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory -- Department of Genetics; Cytogenetics; Drosophila genetics; Evolution; Genetics; Genetics of plants; Genetics Society of America; International Congress of Genetics -- Eighth Congress; Medical research; Radiation genetics; Zea (maize) genetics